# Jae Yong Lee

Sunnyvale, CA

+1 (217)-778-9546 / <u>leejaeyong7@gmail.com</u> / <u>https://jyl.kr</u>

Keywords: Machine Learning, 3D Reconstruction & Rendering, Full-Stack Web Development

## INTRODUCTION

Hello! My name is Jae Yong Lee (Jae) and I am a Machine Learning Engineer at Apple.

Prior to joining Apple, I received my PhD from UIUC under Professor Derek Hoiem, specializing in computer vision. Throughout and prior to my PhD, I've also worked as a computer vision engineer and as a full-stack software engineer at Reconstruct Inc.

I am well-versed in researching novel ideas for computer vision / machine learning algorithms and turning ideas into scalable productions. In particular, I have in-depth experience in designing and experimenting new CV/ML algorithms, optimizing complex ML algorithm runtimes by writing custom first/second order gradient functions in CUDA, developing load-balanced backend system, presenting processed data with interactive frontend interfaces, all the way up to rendering visualizable assets using OpenGL. i.e, from idea to pixels;)

Feel free to reach out if you're interested in my work

### **EDUCATION**

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign	Urbana-Champaign, IL
Ph.D. in Computer Science (Advisor: Derek Hoiem)	2018 - 2023
B.S. in Computer Engineering	2010 - 2016
PROFESSIONAL RESEARCH EXPERIENCE	
Meta Reality Labs	Redmond, WA
Research Intern under Zhaoyang Lv	Summer 2022

Amazon GoSeattle, WAResearch Intern under Chuhang ZouSummer 2021

Microsoft CorporationRedmond, WAResearch Intern under Joseph DegolSummer 2019, Summer 2020

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Apple Inc.	Sunnyvale, CA
Machine Learning Engineer	2024 - Present

Reconstruct Inc.  Urbana-Cha	mpaign, IL
Computer Vision Engineer (Part Time)	2020-2023
Lead Visualization Engineer and Project Manager (Part Time)	2019
Full Stack Developer (Part Time)	2018-2019
Part time developer / Student Intern	2015-2016

Freelance Developer	Seoul, South Korea
Contract 3D Computer Vision Engineer	2016-2018

Republic of Korea Air Force	Osan, South Korea
Staff Sergeant	2011 –2013

# **PUBLICATIONS**

Jae Yong Lee, Yuqun Wu, Chuhang Zou, Derek Hoiem, Shenlong Wang. Plenoptic PNG: Real-Time Neural Radiance Fields in 150 KB. (In submission), 2024

Yuqun Wu\*, Jae Yong Lee\*, Chuhang Zou, Shenlong Wang, Derek Hoiem. MonoPatchNeRF: Improving Neural Radiance Fields with Patch-based Monocular Guidance. Arxiv, 2024

Michal Shlapentokh-Rothman, Ansel Blume, Yao Xiao, Yuqun Wu, Sethuraman T V, Heyi Tao, Jae Yong Lee, Wilfredo Torres, Yu-Xiong Wang, Derek Hoiem. Region-Based Representations Revisited. CVPR, 2024

Jae Yong Lee, Chuhang Zou, Derek Hoiem. Deep PatchMatch MVS with Learned Patch Coplanarity, Geometric Consistency and Adaptive Pixel Sampling. Arxiv, 2022

Jae Yong Lee, Yuqun Wu, Chuhang Zou, Shenlong Wang, and Derek Hoiem. QFF: Quantized Fourier Features for Neural Field Representations. Arxiv, 2022

Yugun Wu\*, Jae Yong Lee\*, Derek Hoiem. Sparse SPN: Depth Completion from Sparse Keypoints. Arxiv. 2022

Liwen Wu, Jae Yong Lee, Anand Bhattad, Yuxiong Wang, David A. Forsyth. DIVeR: Real-time and Accurate Neural Radiance Fields with Deterministic Integration for Volume Rendering. In CVPR, 2022 (Oral Presentation, Best Paper Finalist)

Jae Yong Lee, Joseph DeGol, Chuhang Zou and Derek Hoiem. PatchMatch-RL: Deep MVS with Pixelwise Depth, Normal, and Visibility. In ICCV 2021 (Oral Presentation)

Jae Yong Lee, Joseph DeGol, Victor Fragoso and Sudipta. N. Sinha. PatchMatch-Based Neighborhood Consensus for Semantic Correspondence. In: CVPR. 2021

Jacob J. Lin, Jae Yong Lee and Mani Golparvar-Fard. Exploring the potential of image-based 3d geometry and appearance reasoning for automated construction progress monitoring. In Computing in Civil Engineering 2019: Data, Sensing, and Analytics, 162-170

Joseph DeGol, Jae Yong Lee, Rajbir Kataria, Daniel Yuan, Timothy Bretl and Derek Hoiem. FEATS: Synthetic Feature Tracks for Structure from Motion Evaluation. In 3DV, 2018

#### **TEACHING**

Computational Photography (CS 445)	Urbana-Champaign, IL
Teaching Assistant	Fall 2019

# **AWARDS**

Best Paper Finalist	Urbana-Champaign, IL
Our paper was selected as the Best Paper Finalist in CVPR 2022	2022

#### **Best Vocal Presentation Award** Urbana-Champaign, IL December 2014

As Mentee in Promoting Undergraduate Research, University of Illinois